MUHAMMAD MUNEEB MUSTAFA (Medallist)

(Electrical & Electronic Engineer®)

(PEC#: ELECT-54673)

↑512-A, Gulistan Colony, Faisalabad, Pakistan ↓ +92-306-7022406 ⋈ 92muneebmustafa@gmail.com
Age: 24 years | Marital Status: Single | Nationality: Pakistani

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm equipped with in-depth subject knowledge and practical experience of Electrical Power, Electronics, Robotics, Embedded System, Control System, Signals & System, electronic & Industrial instrumentation, sensors & transducers along with creative PLC programmer committed to providing unique and effective software development solutions also proficient at the testing and assessment of hardware systems, completing troubleshooting and providing sustainable and cost-effective alternatives to existing electrical products and procedures. Moreover, I've leadership qualities like project management and problem solving, analytical attitude filled with artistic qualities such as debater, actor, anchor person, poet and writer.

AREAS OF EXPERTIES AND SKILLS

Technical and Computer Expertise:

- MATLAB
- Proteus, Circuits Design
- Repair & Maintenance
- PLC
- Ardiuno, Microcontrollers
- AutoCad

- HVAC
- Expert in report writing/MS office
- Hardware/Software Installation

Skills and Competencies:

- Strong decision-making.
- Excellent customer facing.
- Excellent communication skills.

- Familiar with Industrial health safety & environment.
- Willingness to work in all weather conditions.
- Analytical Mindset.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (electronics).

(3.71/4 CGPA - Silver Medal)

The University of Faisalabad, Faisalabad, Pakistan.

F.sc (pre-engineering). (1st Div)

Punjab College of Science, Faisalabad, Pakistan.

Matriculation. (1st Div) (May2008 - June2010)

Board of Intermediate & Secondary Education, Faisalabad.

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

PLC (Programmable Logic Control).

(October 2017 – December 2017)

(August 2012 - August 2016)

(August 2010 - June2012)

Punjab Board of Technical Education

- Deep understanding of designing, analysing, fabricating and troubleshooting PLC based control systems.
- Profound knowledge of PLC Ladder Diagram.
- Skilled in HMI programming and its interaction with PLC.
- Knowledge about SCADA.
- Excellent PLC and controls documentation skills.

English Language, Spoken English and Communication Skills Course

(Dec 2015 - March2016)

Punjab English Language Institute

WORK EXPERIENCE

Electrical In-Charge

(August 2018- Present)

United Detergents (Unilever's Products manufacturer company)

Responsibilities

- Responsible of all the electrical work for manufacturing of various Unilever's Products (Surf Excel, Sunlight &Vim).
- Supervise my team for maintenance and repair of electrical & electronic machines.
- Work on control systems (PLC/SCADA/RTU/DCS/HMI) for Industrial & Process Automation.
- Ensure quality control, cost reduction, reliability and performance analysis for Electrical work.
- Conducted electrical troubleshooting on motors, wiring, relays, VFDs, conveyor systems, packaging equipment etc.
- Leadership using hands on management assisting any one in need from troubleshooting to assembly.

Bio Medical Engineer

Madinah Teaching Hospital

Responsibilities

- Electrical and Electronics supports & services for biomedical equipment.
- Purchase, Install, adjust, repair and preventive maintenance for biomedical equipment.
- Evaluate the safety, efficiency, and effectiveness of biomedical equipment.
- Train clinicians and other personnel on the proper use of equipment.
- Setting standards & ensuring their compliance.
- Active involvement in the activities of the hospital's safety committee & checking safety hazards.
- Supervised MRI & CT Chillier troubleshooting and Installed New Chillier for backup.

Lab Engineer

(August 2016 – March 2018)

The University of Faisalabad

Responsibilities

- Design and conduct Electrical, Electronics, PLC, Embedded System and VLSI laboratories exercises.
- Responsible for carrying out teaching and research duties.
- Train Students on the use of PLC & HMI and enhance their practical knowledge.
- Operation, maintenance and inventory of lab equipment and consumables.
- Diagnosing faults and repairing equipment.
- Supervising maintenance and train new technical staff.
- Responsible for the procurement of supplies and equipment.

In charge - Student Affairs Department & Admission Office

(December 2016 – January 2018)

The University of Faisalabad

Responsibilities

- Dealing with students' problems and issues.
- Event Organization.
- Societies' management.
- University marketing.

- Students counselling.
- Maintaining alumni records and network.
- Supervising admission office.
- Upgrading admission record.

Internee Electrical Engineer

(June 2014 - July 2014)

Northern Power Generation Company Limited (GENCO-III), Faisalabad

Responsibilities

On getting the opportunity to work in central workshop, gas turbine station, and steam power station. I managed to grab some practical experience of materialization of theoretical knowledge into practice and got the hands on experience by working with transformers, turbines, troubleshooting of gas powered generators.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

Military Based Robotic Tank (ICT Funded & National level 1st position)

(May 2016)

Above cited Tank system was designed, developed and carried out by me in my Final Year Project.

Description: I was an automated robotic system developed for the purpose of detection of enemy using camera though image processing technique. We can control robot and firing system from base station GUI, get live video and audio streaming. It has ability to self-drive on a given map. Thus, users can easily control the Robot in anytime, anywhere over an internet connection.

Spy Robot

• Object Detection by Ultrasonic

Wireless Control of Robotic Arm

PROFESSIONAL & ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENT

- 2nd position (Silver Medallist) in Bachelor of Electrical Engineering and 1st position in Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (electronics) 2012-16 session, The University of Faisalabad.
- Awarded with Gold Medal for best performer, The University of Faisalabad. (2015)
- Awarded with ICT R&D funding of maximum range for my final year project.
- Won 1st position in all Pakistan Project Competition held in University of Gujrat. (June 2016)
- Won "Bomb disposal robot" 2nd Position in all Pakistan Project competition Organized by University of Guirat.(December 2015)
- 1st position in Allama Iqbal Shield inters university debating competition held by HEC, 2016.
- 1st position in Faisalabad board level Urdu debate competition held by BISE Faisalabad, 2009.

REFERENES

Will be furnished on demand.

(March 2018 – July 2018)